Ahmad B. Usman

 ♦ Linköping Sweden
 ☑ ahmadbash.usman@gmail.com
 ♣ 070 301 57 07
 � ahmadbashusman.github.io

 in ahmadbashusman
 ♠ ahmadbashusman

Summary _

I am a Cyber Security researcher with a passion for Ethical Hacking and Penetration Testing as well as Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning technologies.

Personal Information _____

Nationality: Nigeria

Place & Date of Birth: Saudi Arabia 1993

Education _____

MSc in ICT for Internet and Multimedia: University of Padua (Italy)

Oct 2019 – July 2021

• Track of CyberSystems, Dept. of Information Engineering: GPA: 110/110 Thesis 🗹

BSc in Information Technology: University of Science and Technology (Sudan)

Oct 2013 - Sep 2017

• Faculty of Computer Science & Information Technology: GPA: 3.78/4

Experience _____

Linköping University, Research Assistant

Linköping, Sweden Dec 2021 – Present

 $\bullet \ \ Conducting \ research \ on \ Secure \ software \ updates \ and \ remote \ attestation$

Verona, Italy

HWG s.r.l, Cyber Security Specialist

Ongoing security management

Sep 2021 – Nov 2021

SPRITZ, Research Assistant

• Conducting research on Industrial Control Systems and Machine learning

Padua, Italy Sep 2020 – Jul 2021

Certificate _____

Certified Ethical Hacker (CEH): EC-Council, Dec 2017.

Security+: CampTIA, Sep 2017 **CCNA Security:** CISCO, Aug 2017.

CCNA Routing/Switching: CISCO, Sep 2015.

Publications

Remote Attestation with Software Updates in Embedded Systems

Oct 2024

• Ahmad B. Usman and Mikael Asplund IEEE ☑

Remote Attestation Assurance Arguments for Trusted Execution Environments

Apr 2023

• Ahmad B. Usman, N. Cole, Mikael Asplund, F. Boeira, C. Vestlund ACM 🗹

Other Skills _____

Programming: C++, C, Python, SQL, Java, JavaScript

Languages: English (H), Arabic (H), Swedish (M), Hausa (H)